<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>poem on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/poem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in poem on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:28:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/poem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>sometimes</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/sometimes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A life is a gust of wind.
It will pass by and rattle the leaves of trees firmly planted in the ground.
It will make its presence known and then fade away.
It will pass so quickly that the forest will label it merely a tourist.
Only the leaf can measure the strength of the wind.
The leaf is driven to move and provoked to hiss, but even a leaf’s tantrum can’t attract enough attention.
It takes a storm for the forest to notice – a big storm.
And even storms are common.
Perhaps a tornado or a hurricane instead. A gust is worthless and meaningless.
Sometimes you forget your own existence.
You look around at this foreign place called Earth.
You see people, and you see their habits, emotions, and behaviors. And then you try to put the pieces together and gather a grasping of why.
Place yourself in a any large gathering, in a random town, looking at a sea of unknown but familiar faces.
You’ve never met any of these people, yet you can observe them, and you can acknowledge for a few moments that you aren’t the main protagonist in this literary epic called “mankind”.
These people have lives.
In this small room, you see a mountain in each person.
They were weathered and molded by the people who surround them and what they believe in.
It was only for a moment, but you left yourself.
Now, you’re back inside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>