<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>time on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/time/</link>
    <description>Recent content in time on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 21:30:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/time/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>time to eat</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/timetoeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/timetoeat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to eat. This city has a bountiful selection: burger joints, pizzerias, taquerias, thai food, indian food, barbeque, pub grub, shawarma, noodles. And so on. Some cities are luckier than others. Too many folks waste their time looking for that five star steak dinner. There’s nothing wrong with a steak dinner every now and then. And gourmet food is excellent. However, there’s so many ways to satisfy a deep hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can still avoid junk food. One can still limit dessert. But regular consumption is important for survival and a good artist must never be hungry. Hunger is a distraction. Would Picasso have been able to finish “Les Demoiselles d&amp;rsquo;Avignon” if his stomach was growling? Would Hemingway have completed “The Sun Also Rises” on an empty fuel tank? The answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People eat food all hours of the day. Their teeth sink into oozing hand-held sources of glory. Meanwhile, the hungry take that vision and fight to make it their reality.
Don’t starve. Now is the time while we’re all young. The food is ready, so get it while it’s hot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>