<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>flash fiction on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/flash-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in flash fiction on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 21:28:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/flash-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>martha</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/martha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/martha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time we arrived with the ambulance, the body was a motionless ragdoll on the kitchen floor. She was strangled by her husband, who was still coming down from a concoction of rage, sorrow, and alcohol when we kicked the door open. Crimson splotches covered his shirt, and an eight-year old little girl was sobbing behind the living room sofa. We had to help the man because he was injured. Blood was dripping from a gash in his torso. Martha, one of the EMTs, dragged him to the ambulance. I could see each breath enter and then exit Martha’s nostrils. She didn’t look at me when she passed. Her body was like a wooden 2x4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I watched her and another tend to the husband’s wounds I could see a visible shift in Martha’s face. Her eyes changed. She gained this sinister aura. She lifted her fingers from a bandage she applied and raised them to the man’s face. She jabbed her fingers into his eyes. He screamed and wailed and hollered in pain. The other EMTs froze. Before she could crush his eyes, I leapt forward and yanked Martha by the shoulder away from the man. He fell over unconscious. We sat in the ambulance in silence until the police arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>heaven</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rays of morning sunlight pierced through the curtains. The alarm was ringing from across the room. I rolled out of bed and my feet touched the cold floor of my cuboidal apartment. After turning off the alarm, I walked over to the closet and stared at seven identical gray outfits. There’s a set of pants and a button down shirt for each day of the week. I picked out the first set and got dressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still getting used to life here in heaven. Back when I was alive and living on earth, people told me all these things about pearly gates and lush green gardens. It’s not quite like that.
First of all, there is no such thing as food in heaven. There is no need for it as we are never hungry. No food, no restaurants, no bars, no toilets. And everyone has a job in heaven. Don’t expect to come here and do nothing. You’re assigned a job based on the talents, or lack thereof, you held back home on earth. Everyone is given one square dormitorium to be their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after I got dressed, I hurried downstairs and outside. The streets were filled with people flowing like conflicting currents. These people got places to be. It’s a fast paced world up here and there’s no time to be wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My job was to report to the wall. The one I’m talking about is the mile high concrete wall that wraps around the entirety of heaven. It may be daunting in appearance, but a closer look reveals fractures and scars. The wall has one purpose: to keep those who didn’t make it to heaven out. As you might imagine, not making it to heaven is a serious thing. This is the afterlife which, unlike regular life, is infinite. It lasts forever. If you don’t make it to heaven, you’re stuck. Sorry, pal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rejected from heaven can spark intense emotional reactions in people. Everyone wants to come here, but only those who are qualified are allowed in. The man in charge is very selective.
Every day, I come to the wall and scale a long treacherous ladder to then climb to the other side of the wall. That’s correct,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go to the other side. Why? Well, to clean it. The other side of the wall, the one that’s facing the void nothingness that isn’t heaven, is littered with graffiti and vandalism. There are cracks and wounds left over from all the people who couldn’t get in and were very angry about that. Every time someone gets rejected, their immediate reaction is to throw a tantrum and pound and kick against the wall. Others write profane words and slurs. And some spend days dousing the surface of the concrete with violent colors. I have to scrub it all off. The man in charge likes to keep it clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did you hear about the new guy?” my boss asked me.
I shrugged my shoulders. Apparently there’s a new guy in our group. I saw my coworkers traversing over to the wall, and near the front of the pack was a chipper looking guy with a smile that filled his face. He clearly just died. This had to be his first or second day in heaven. They always arrive cheery and excited.
“What are you gonna have him do?” I asked.
“Well, everybody hates scrubbing those dick drawings. So I figured I’d make him do it for his first day. That’ll set him straight”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lucky</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/lucky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For four years, I was homeless. I lived under the bridge, the one that goes over the train tracks and out over the river. The howling train was my morning alarm. That, accompanied with the sound of college crew teams rowing in the water.
My makeshift mattress was good enough. The stack of rugs and wool blankets did its job. A cohort of wild animals and graffiti smothered structures kept me company. When I was up to it, I would leave my little habitat and walk all the way into town, hoping to scrounge up food with whatever money I had gathered. Sometimes, I would go all the way to the library and read some books because it’s warm there in the winter time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I decided I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live this life anymore. I needed to get a job and move on with my life. So, I found the cheapest button-down shirt I could bargain at a flea market. I had no iron. All I could do was try and stretch out the wrinkles. With my wet and hand-combed hair I went to the diner on Hansen and applied for a job.
I have to admit, I lied about my experience. I told them that I had done this before and that I worked at all these different blue-collar jobs before coming here. And I guess I just got lucky because they gave me a job in the kitchen cooking food.
I never cooked a single plate of food up until then. Not a single piece of meat. Not even pasta or soup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was this middle aged lady, must&amp;rsquo;ve been in her early 40&amp;rsquo;s. Clearly she was from around these parts and probably was working this job for a long time. She enjoyed it, no doubt. She was sort of like my superior and she would help me out a little bit and train me. She knew that I lied. But she must&amp;rsquo;ve known how bad I needed this job. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even slice a goddam bell pepper right. This lady, her name I wish I could remember, she really saved me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She never said a word to the manager. And I know sometimes I would make her mad because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do anything right, but she was so patient. She talked to this other guy who used to clean the pots and the pans at the end of the night. He helped me find an apartment. I had to lie to the landlord because I was only making 12 dollars an hour under the table. The work was intense in the beginning. Everything went so fast and sometimes I would mess up. But I wanted to be good. In my spare time I would read cookbooks and I would even go to the library to use the computers. I would watch videos to learn different cooking skills. I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop until I knew everything about how to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t work at that diner anymore. But I think back to that time and how I struggled but I was able to get through it all. And that lady, I wish I remembered her name. If she ever reads this, I just wanted to say, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hamburgers</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/hamburgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/hamburgers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There I was, snoozing on the job and my dreams were loud. The time was three a.m. on a mild autumn night and I sat slouched in a chair, breathing in spurts with a bottle of cola between my thighs. The sound of the rattling bell startled me awake. Without warning, the world ripped me from the depths and brought me back to the surface. My eyes fluttered open, heart was pounding a steady beat shooting life through my veins. I was upstairs in the firehouse and only dressed from the waste down in my uniform. I realized what was happening. This was my first fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“PARKER? Where are you? Let’s go!” the chief called from down below. The crew was sprinting out to the fire trucks.
I leaped out of the chair, pulled my straps up, threw my jacket on, and tied my boots. All the while, I couldn’t help but ask, “How did I get here?”. Y’know when you’re half between asleep and awake and you start asking yourself all these existential questions? But then, I reminded myself that it was better here than overseas on the front lines. You see, I became a firefighter to escape the draft. And my mother. This was fate’s way of saying, “Here you go. This is what you asked for”.
I slid down the metal pole to the garage. The rest of the crew were getting settled in the trucks. My buddy Randall was in the driver’s seat and so I hopped in next to him. I pretended to look like I wasn’t petrified. The engines turned on and we were in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night, the rural roads are quiet and desolate. Randall turned on the flashing lights without sounding the siren. Sounds of the truck breathing and barreling down the road echoed through the open land. I stared at dark corn fields and silhouettes of little houses in the distance. They stood peacefully, like murky images in a painting. Behind them was a clear sky backdrop. Each star was a buoyant lantern in a black sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Were you sleepin’ upstairs, Parker?” Randall turned to me and laughed. I smirked and shook my head in embarrassment.
An orange glow broke the darkness. Our truck sped down unpaved gravel towards the source of the light.
“Here we are. Another barn burner, am I right?” Randall said. I felt my heartbeat shake my body.
We arrived at the scene of a farm, subdued by waves of fire. The old man was bare chested. His wife in her nightgown and they were both pouring buckets of water on the flames. When I opened the door to the truck, I was greeted by the strong smell of hamburgers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain yelled, “PARKER, GET THAT HOSE!”
I pulled the long grey tube and ran into the grass towards a barn. The farmer’s wife was sobbing. There was a charred cow lying dead on the ground. The horses were trotting away into the fields. The hose in my arms turned on and water erupted from the nozzle. I held on with all my strength and smothered as much of the fire as I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old couple gathered their chickens and goats to safety away from the torched barn. Piece by piece, the water swallowed the raging flames until they were squelched. Within several minutes, the job was done. But at the end of the night, the old couple lost two cows and needed a lot of work to fix what burned down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that week, I was sitting at my desk when Randall strolled in, holding a newspaper. He held it up and said, “Read this,” tossing it into my hands.
“POLICE PINCH PYROMANIAC!” read the headline. There was a picture of a dirty middle-aged man in handcuffs. “Serial arsonist arrested by police in Colorado. Left a trail of barn fires in his path”.
The man fled Omaha, running away from a warrant for his arrest. He thought it would be better to burn out than to fade away. Thankfully, justice was served.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>