<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>man on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/man/</link>
    <description>Recent content in man on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 21:30:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/man/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>man or wolf?</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/manorwolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/manorwolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guillermo San Martin was once a feral child. The wolf cubs that roam the Sierra Morena accepted him as their brother. That was many years ago. Now he is an aging and decaying man with gray hairs. He lives in a small cottage outside Ourense, and he’s unsatisfied with being human. This past winter was long and difficult. His frail body now aches and his chest is filled with phlegm. And to him, the human world is just as cold, if not colder than the winters he can barely withstand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child he was fed by the mother wolf. He survived on whatever meat was scavenged and various plants and berries. He was a hunter too and could kill with his rocks or tree branches. He slept in the caves, accompanied by the bats. For seventeen years, he was half man, half wolf.
One day, he was found by the Civil Guard. He was wrapped in deerskin and spoke no words of castellano. He could only grunt and whine the way the wolves taught him to. His hair was long and ragged and his body emanated an untamed stench. And so the Civil Guard laughed at him and mocked him in his presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Look at this fool,” they pointed.
Without hesitation, they seized his arms. He flailed and shouted and screamed. But the other wolves were afraid of the humans. They didn’t come to help him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Civil Guard took him back to civilization. Thorough haircut. He was scrubbed and loused and squeezed into clothes to make him somewhat acceptable for human interaction. Nails clipped. Teeth scraped. The monks in the monastery held his wrists and forcefully taught him how to clean himself. Wearing shoes made walking painful as they squeezed his calloused feet. He was thrown into a fast, vile, and shifting world. At night, he was tutored. He learned to speak, read, and write. In the day, he worked with his hands, assisting in construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People cheated him. They abused him. He was broke and struggled to find a lover. And this is the story of many. We tried to help him, believe me. Some are put-off by his awkwardness. And he can see it in the silent language their faces speak. No one believes him. He’s a hunter-gatherer in a world that raises its eyebrow at him. He’s useless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>