<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>virtual on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/virtual/</link>
    <description>Recent content in virtual on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:30:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/virtual/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>la loma</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/laloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/laloma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classes were over and the sky was darkening. I trekked down to the cyber café on 14th street. I wanted to get in a quick virtual session before I engaged in my much needed social interaction of the evening. This particular cyber café is the only one on the north coast. One might say it’s a luxury. I’m surprised it’s still around considering our cultural stance on superfluous things. Going inside the café, it’s best to wear sunglasses as not to hurt your eyes from all the glowing lights. Flashy gizmos and screens fill the place for your pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a ride on the yellow line to Arborway. No one else got off at the stop, so I expected the place wouldn’t be crowded. This was good, as I hoped to avoid running into friends. I don’t go to the cyber cafe to socialize. In fact, I go to do quite the opposite. This was a time for solitude and individual mediation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening the door to the café was like opening a magic box. The bells strapped to the top of the door frame jingled as I swung it open. The place was burning blue with light. Soft cushioned seats lay scattered across the lounge area. Each individual one was an odd geometric shape. Dodecahedrons, cylinders, rectangular prisms, et cetera. High tables had built-in touch screens emanating a digital world. People could sit on stools, and poke around on little arcade games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walls were brick painted black and married to avant-garde art. The smell of coffee assaulted my nostrils. Ambient music seeped through the speakers hanging in the corners of the walls. Layers of winding chords streaked under sparse keyboard notes.
My prediction was correct. The place was quiet at this hour. I timed my visit perfectly, because most people use their Friday evenings for more social based activities. Social interaction. There were a couple of girls sitting on pentagonal prism seats in the back staring at the wall of screens. Each screen showed a different channel. One had a motion picture. Another showed a live concert. And another had a cartoon. With a pair of headphones, one can choose which audio from which screen he or she wants to hear with a click of a button. One screen’s audio can play in one ear while another plays in the opposite ear, allowing for dual absorption. A person could listen to one show while glancing at another, accumulating a collage of sensory experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the far right was a bar. Behind the counter in cabinets were portable headsets and handheld devices to be rented out to customers. There was a row of plastic seats against one wall, each in companion with a footrest. For $300 at the counter, you can get a pair of goggles to strap to your head that fits a small chip the size of a quarter. The small chip contains a mind-numbing, alternate world of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I walked up to the guy at the counter. He was cleaning a mug once filled with a beverage.
“Can I get the one with the restaurant? La Loma?” I asked.
He reached into the cabinet, snatched the chip, and slapped it down on the counter. He then grabbed a pair of goggles from a shelf and handed them to me. The guy must get dozens of people like me every day.
“Enjoy,” he said and I handed him a $300 bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get thirty minutes. Just thirty minutes to travel to a place you’ve never experienced or touched before. It’s all in your head but it feels completely real. The sights are clear, the scents are potent, and the textures are palpable.
Sometimes, people want a refill. They just pay the $300 again and again and again so they can stay in their nirvana. All so they can disappear to their fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat down in the leather seat against the wall and strapped on the goggles. It was a full head apparatus. It covered the ears, the eyes and the nose like a mask. I strapped down my waist to the chair. I clicked the button connected to the goggles and was taken to my place of choice: a deck facing the sea in a restaurant called La Loma. It was the only chip I ever bought. Every time I come to the cafe, I get this exact one, because it’s my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chip was designed well. This entire experience, in my opinion, is the pinnacle of art. First, we were given literature and music and paintings. Then we were given photographs and motion pictures. After that we played video games. But now, we have synthetic worlds designed by even brighter men and women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each setting is a masterpiece in its own right. We can see what they want us to see, feel what they want us to feel, hear, touch, and smell. It’s like reality, but not, at the same time. It can be if we choose. We can ignore the real world and indulge in our fantasies for periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Loma was my guilty pleasure. It’s set looking out at a sea dubbed “the Mediterranean,” an exotic name I would have never conjured up myself. And perhaps that’s why it’s so captivating. Someone invented that word. Someone had the imagination to put a restaurant against this backdrop. People fill the seats at the tables and talk through their programmed conversations. They sound the same every time. I know because I eavesdrop on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seagulls cried like sirens in the distance. A thin cloud of fog hovered over the rocks near the water. I could barely hear the music playing nearby because of the constant conversations around me. Platinum utensils clanged against porcelain plates and the smell of food invaded my nose. But my favorite part was not the luxury. It wasn’t that feeling of being high class and attractive. My favorite part was not the gorgeous outlook. It wasn’t even the breathtaking architecture. My favorite part was the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Would you like anything to drink?” a waitress interrupted my daydream.
She was wearing a fancy black dress. Truthfully, everyone in La Loma was wearing high class attire. It was different from life in the north coast. However, I didn’t care for any of it. Clothes don’t interest me. And why should they? They serve a utilitarian purpose. Why waste time deciding what dress you’re going to wear when you don’t have to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Can, can I have a glass of, wine?” I stuttered and she nodded.
I felt it was an appropriate thing to have in this occasion. In the real world, I prefer not to drink. The waitress brought me my glass of wine and I stared out at the so-called “Mediterranean” while I drank. I felt the maroon colored liquid enter my lips and splash upon my tongue. It’s dark rich flavor invoked images of a thousand fruits gushing across my taste buds.
Behind me were tables seating guests amidst conversations. I turned and looked at them. These half-human constituents of the scene were not programmed to react exactly as a real person would. They don’t mind when I stare at them or when I listen intently to what they say without any contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard, “Se casó con esa dama. Ya tú sabe”.
“¿Cuánto tiempo se conocen?” said another.
“Seis meses”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were speaking some made up language that I didn’t understand. And perhaps that’s the point. They weren’t saying anything at all. Plain gibberish. It leads me to wonder about the motives of the artist behind this place. Whoever was the genius who did the design, left it all open ended. I can interpret their nonsensical language to be whatever I want it to be.
When my thirty minutes were over, I felt fulfilled. I eavesdropped on conversations. I stared directly into faces. I couldn’t do these things in the real world. But all of these things I could do without consequence while eating dinner at La Loma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>