<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EMT on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/emt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in EMT on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 21:28:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/emt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>martha</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/martha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/martha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time we arrived with the ambulance, the body was a motionless ragdoll on the kitchen floor. She was strangled by her husband, who was still coming down from a concoction of rage, sorrow, and alcohol when we kicked the door open. Crimson splotches covered his shirt, and an eight-year old little girl was sobbing behind the living room sofa. We had to help the man because he was injured. Blood was dripping from a gash in his torso. Martha, one of the EMTs, dragged him to the ambulance. I could see each breath enter and then exit Martha’s nostrils. She didn’t look at me when she passed. Her body was like a wooden 2x4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I watched her and another tend to the husband’s wounds I could see a visible shift in Martha’s face. Her eyes changed. She gained this sinister aura. She lifted her fingers from a bandage she applied and raised them to the man’s face. She jabbed her fingers into his eyes. He screamed and wailed and hollered in pain. The other EMTs froze. Before she could crush his eyes, I leapt forward and yanked Martha by the shoulder away from the man. He fell over unconscious. We sat in the ambulance in silence until the police arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>