<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/</link>
    <description>Recent content on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 21:30:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>time to eat</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/timetoeat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/timetoeat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s time to eat. This city has a bountiful selection: burger joints, pizzerias, taquerias, thai food, indian food, barbeque, pub grub, shawarma, noodles. And so on. Some cities are luckier than others. Too many folks waste their time looking for that five star steak dinner. There’s nothing wrong with a steak dinner every now and then. And gourmet food is excellent. However, there’s so many ways to satisfy a deep hunger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One can still avoid junk food. One can still limit dessert. But regular consumption is important for survival and a good artist must never be hungry. Hunger is a distraction. Would Picasso have been able to finish “Les Demoiselles d&amp;rsquo;Avignon” if his stomach was growling? Would Hemingway have completed “The Sun Also Rises” on an empty fuel tank? The answer is no.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People eat food all hours of the day. Their teeth sink into oozing hand-held sources of glory. Meanwhile, the hungry take that vision and fight to make it their reality.
Don’t starve. Now is the time while we’re all young. The food is ready, so get it while it’s hot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>man or wolf?</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/manorwolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/manorwolf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Guillermo San Martin was once a feral child. The wolf cubs that roam the Sierra Morena accepted him as their brother. That was many years ago. Now he is an aging and decaying man with gray hairs. He lives in a small cottage outside Ourense, and he’s unsatisfied with being human. This past winter was long and difficult. His frail body now aches and his chest is filled with phlegm. And to him, the human world is just as cold, if not colder than the winters he can barely withstand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child he was fed by the mother wolf. He survived on whatever meat was scavenged and various plants and berries. He was a hunter too and could kill with his rocks or tree branches. He slept in the caves, accompanied by the bats. For seventeen years, he was half man, half wolf.
One day, he was found by the Civil Guard. He was wrapped in deerskin and spoke no words of castellano. He could only grunt and whine the way the wolves taught him to. His hair was long and ragged and his body emanated an untamed stench. And so the Civil Guard laughed at him and mocked him in his presence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Look at this fool,” they pointed.
Without hesitation, they seized his arms. He flailed and shouted and screamed. But the other wolves were afraid of the humans. They didn’t come to help him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Civil Guard took him back to civilization. Thorough haircut. He was scrubbed and loused and squeezed into clothes to make him somewhat acceptable for human interaction. Nails clipped. Teeth scraped. The monks in the monastery held his wrists and forcefully taught him how to clean himself. Wearing shoes made walking painful as they squeezed his calloused feet. He was thrown into a fast, vile, and shifting world. At night, he was tutored. He learned to speak, read, and write. In the day, he worked with his hands, assisting in construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People cheated him. They abused him. He was broke and struggled to find a lover. And this is the story of many. We tried to help him, believe me. Some are put-off by his awkwardness. And he can see it in the silent language their faces speak. No one believes him. He’s a hunter-gatherer in a world that raises its eyebrow at him. He’s useless.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>edge of the world</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/edgeoftheworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/edgeoftheworld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It started with how she would keep her towel wrapped around her after she came out of the shower. We were married for three years and suddenly she was ashamed to walk around the bedroom naked. Then came an abundance of silence at the dinner table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So how was your day?” “Good”. Then came the nights when she would come home late without any explanation. And then came the divorce papers. It felt like I was falling face first into the pavement in slow motion. I saw the impending crash, but it couldn’t happen fast enough. Three years gone. My nice apartment gone. Most of my furniture and appliances gone too. Three years of just a foggy dream and now I was awake and raw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was heavily involved in the Silicon Valley tech scene. But the gig was turning sour. After the divorce, I started to slouch. I was showing up later and later. My work was getting sloppier. And this all came to a head when I showed up one Monday hungover and disheveled. Shirt stained and unbuttoned. Hair uncombed. And then, BANG. Just like that. Fired.
The stinging pain started to settle in. I thought about what to do. My life was reset, not by choice, but by force. It only took a small accident and a little nudge to get me moving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One morning I woke up to find a magazine in my mailbox. It was addressed to the wrong person. The magazine said, “A Traveler’s Guide to Alaska”. And all these thoughts infected me. I called J. He was my best friend in the whole wide world, and it felt like he was all I had left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said, “yes,” almost immediately. In fact, I was hesitant and he had to convince me.
“This can be an important moment for us,” he said. And then I thought about my life and how I wasn’t even thirty yet. I was still young despite feeling like I lived a million years devoid of any meaningful accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was to ride north on our motorcycles until the road ran out. Two gentlemen- two compatriots riding ten-thousand miles until the ground turns lifeless on the cusp of the Arctic Sea. No turning back until we reach the edge of the world.
I expected things to go wrong and for there to be challenges. But that only excited me more. I needed something to push back against. I needed the forces of nature to try and bludgeon me down into the ground so I could muscle myself back up with all my strength. I fight harder on the comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I geared up my Harley and J geared up his Ducati. And boy, are they beautiful bikes in looks and in sound. But to take on the Great Frontier we had to make some modifications: better tires, rugged panniers, protective covering, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later, on a typical morning in San Francisco, we began our journey. Breakfast at the diner was fast and filling. We said goodbye to friends from town. After some morning caffeine, we cruised across the Golden Gate Bridge and made our way onto the windy Route 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coastal cliffs were jagged. Currents of wind flowed through me. The fields danced between bone-dry yellow and lush green. As we raced through Northern California, the terrain grew larger and the greens grew darker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>martha</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/martha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/martha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time we arrived with the ambulance, the body was a motionless ragdoll on the kitchen floor. She was strangled by her husband, who was still coming down from a concoction of rage, sorrow, and alcohol when we kicked the door open. Crimson splotches covered his shirt, and an eight-year old little girl was sobbing behind the living room sofa. We had to help the man because he was injured. Blood was dripping from a gash in his torso. Martha, one of the EMTs, dragged him to the ambulance. I could see each breath enter and then exit Martha’s nostrils. She didn’t look at me when she passed. Her body was like a wooden 2x4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I watched her and another tend to the husband’s wounds I could see a visible shift in Martha’s face. Her eyes changed. She gained this sinister aura. She lifted her fingers from a bandage she applied and raised them to the man’s face. She jabbed her fingers into his eyes. He screamed and wailed and hollered in pain. The other EMTs froze. Before she could crush his eyes, I leapt forward and yanked Martha by the shoulder away from the man. He fell over unconscious. We sat in the ambulance in silence until the police arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>heaven</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/heaven/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rays of morning sunlight pierced through the curtains. The alarm was ringing from across the room. I rolled out of bed and my feet touched the cold floor of my cuboidal apartment. After turning off the alarm, I walked over to the closet and stared at seven identical gray outfits. There’s a set of pants and a button down shirt for each day of the week. I picked out the first set and got dressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still getting used to life here in heaven. Back when I was alive and living on earth, people told me all these things about pearly gates and lush green gardens. It’s not quite like that.
First of all, there is no such thing as food in heaven. There is no need for it as we are never hungry. No food, no restaurants, no bars, no toilets. And everyone has a job in heaven. Don’t expect to come here and do nothing. You’re assigned a job based on the talents, or lack thereof, you held back home on earth. Everyone is given one square dormitorium to be their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So after I got dressed, I hurried downstairs and outside. The streets were filled with people flowing like conflicting currents. These people got places to be. It’s a fast paced world up here and there’s no time to be wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My job was to report to the wall. The one I’m talking about is the mile high concrete wall that wraps around the entirety of heaven. It may be daunting in appearance, but a closer look reveals fractures and scars. The wall has one purpose: to keep those who didn’t make it to heaven out. As you might imagine, not making it to heaven is a serious thing. This is the afterlife which, unlike regular life, is infinite. It lasts forever. If you don’t make it to heaven, you’re stuck. Sorry, pal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting rejected from heaven can spark intense emotional reactions in people. Everyone wants to come here, but only those who are qualified are allowed in. The man in charge is very selective.
Every day, I come to the wall and scale a long treacherous ladder to then climb to the other side of the wall. That’s correct,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go to the other side. Why? Well, to clean it. The other side of the wall, the one that’s facing the void nothingness that isn’t heaven, is littered with graffiti and vandalism. There are cracks and wounds left over from all the people who couldn’t get in and were very angry about that. Every time someone gets rejected, their immediate reaction is to throw a tantrum and pound and kick against the wall. Others write profane words and slurs. And some spend days dousing the surface of the concrete with violent colors. I have to scrub it all off. The man in charge likes to keep it clean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Did you hear about the new guy?” my boss asked me.
I shrugged my shoulders. Apparently there’s a new guy in our group. I saw my coworkers traversing over to the wall, and near the front of the pack was a chipper looking guy with a smile that filled his face. He clearly just died. This had to be his first or second day in heaven. They always arrive cheery and excited.
“What are you gonna have him do?” I asked.
“Well, everybody hates scrubbing those dick drawings. So I figured I’d make him do it for his first day. That’ll set him straight”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lucky</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/lucky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/lucky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For four years, I was homeless. I lived under the bridge, the one that goes over the train tracks and out over the river. The howling train was my morning alarm. That, accompanied with the sound of college crew teams rowing in the water.
My makeshift mattress was good enough. The stack of rugs and wool blankets did its job. A cohort of wild animals and graffiti smothered structures kept me company. When I was up to it, I would leave my little habitat and walk all the way into town, hoping to scrounge up food with whatever money I had gathered. Sometimes, I would go all the way to the library and read some books because it’s warm there in the winter time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually, I decided I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live this life anymore. I needed to get a job and move on with my life. So, I found the cheapest button-down shirt I could bargain at a flea market. I had no iron. All I could do was try and stretch out the wrinkles. With my wet and hand-combed hair I went to the diner on Hansen and applied for a job.
I have to admit, I lied about my experience. I told them that I had done this before and that I worked at all these different blue-collar jobs before coming here. And I guess I just got lucky because they gave me a job in the kitchen cooking food.
I never cooked a single plate of food up until then. Not a single piece of meat. Not even pasta or soup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was this middle aged lady, must&amp;rsquo;ve been in her early 40&amp;rsquo;s. Clearly she was from around these parts and probably was working this job for a long time. She enjoyed it, no doubt. She was sort of like my superior and she would help me out a little bit and train me. She knew that I lied. But she must&amp;rsquo;ve known how bad I needed this job. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even slice a goddam bell pepper right. This lady, her name I wish I could remember, she really saved me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She never said a word to the manager. And I know sometimes I would make her mad because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t do anything right, but she was so patient. She talked to this other guy who used to clean the pots and the pans at the end of the night. He helped me find an apartment. I had to lie to the landlord because I was only making 12 dollars an hour under the table. The work was intense in the beginning. Everything went so fast and sometimes I would mess up. But I wanted to be good. In my spare time I would read cookbooks and I would even go to the library to use the computers. I would watch videos to learn different cooking skills. I didn&amp;rsquo;t stop until I knew everything about how to cook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t work at that diner anymore. But I think back to that time and how I struggled but I was able to get through it all. And that lady, I wish I remembered her name. If she ever reads this, I just wanted to say, thanks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hamburgers</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/hamburgers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/hamburgers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There I was, snoozing on the job and my dreams were loud. The time was three a.m. on a mild autumn night and I sat slouched in a chair, breathing in spurts with a bottle of cola between my thighs. The sound of the rattling bell startled me awake. Without warning, the world ripped me from the depths and brought me back to the surface. My eyes fluttered open, heart was pounding a steady beat shooting life through my veins. I was upstairs in the firehouse and only dressed from the waste down in my uniform. I realized what was happening. This was my first fire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“PARKER? Where are you? Let’s go!” the chief called from down below. The crew was sprinting out to the fire trucks.
I leaped out of the chair, pulled my straps up, threw my jacket on, and tied my boots. All the while, I couldn’t help but ask, “How did I get here?”. Y’know when you’re half between asleep and awake and you start asking yourself all these existential questions? But then, I reminded myself that it was better here than overseas on the front lines. You see, I became a firefighter to escape the draft. And my mother. This was fate’s way of saying, “Here you go. This is what you asked for”.
I slid down the metal pole to the garage. The rest of the crew were getting settled in the trucks. My buddy Randall was in the driver’s seat and so I hopped in next to him. I pretended to look like I wasn’t petrified. The engines turned on and we were in motion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night, the rural roads are quiet and desolate. Randall turned on the flashing lights without sounding the siren. Sounds of the truck breathing and barreling down the road echoed through the open land. I stared at dark corn fields and silhouettes of little houses in the distance. They stood peacefully, like murky images in a painting. Behind them was a clear sky backdrop. Each star was a buoyant lantern in a black sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Were you sleepin’ upstairs, Parker?” Randall turned to me and laughed. I smirked and shook my head in embarrassment.
An orange glow broke the darkness. Our truck sped down unpaved gravel towards the source of the light.
“Here we are. Another barn burner, am I right?” Randall said. I felt my heartbeat shake my body.
We arrived at the scene of a farm, subdued by waves of fire. The old man was bare chested. His wife in her nightgown and they were both pouring buckets of water on the flames. When I opened the door to the truck, I was greeted by the strong smell of hamburgers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Captain yelled, “PARKER, GET THAT HOSE!”
I pulled the long grey tube and ran into the grass towards a barn. The farmer’s wife was sobbing. There was a charred cow lying dead on the ground. The horses were trotting away into the fields. The hose in my arms turned on and water erupted from the nozzle. I held on with all my strength and smothered as much of the fire as I could.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old couple gathered their chickens and goats to safety away from the torched barn. Piece by piece, the water swallowed the raging flames until they were squelched. Within several minutes, the job was done. But at the end of the night, the old couple lost two cows and needed a lot of work to fix what burned down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later that week, I was sitting at my desk when Randall strolled in, holding a newspaper. He held it up and said, “Read this,” tossing it into my hands.
“POLICE PINCH PYROMANIAC!” read the headline. There was a picture of a dirty middle-aged man in handcuffs. “Serial arsonist arrested by police in Colorado. Left a trail of barn fires in his path”.
The man fled Omaha, running away from a warrant for his arrest. He thought it would be better to burn out than to fade away. Thankfully, justice was served.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gentle meadows</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/gentle-meadows/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:32:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/gentle-meadows/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The kids are inside and it’s a beautiful day. The streets are quiet in the monotony of suburbia. I sit on the pavement of a dilapidated public basketball court listening to someone’s dog bark at me from a window. The asphalt is rough, filled with craters, and cracked like the scene of a miniature earthquake. Lush and unrelenting green grass seeps through the cavernous cracks in the ground. Nature tried to reclaim its dominion over this man-made structure. The white lines that divide the court are fading into nonexistence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>la loma</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/laloma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/laloma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Classes were over and the sky was darkening. I trekked down to the cyber café on 14th street. I wanted to get in a quick virtual session before I engaged in my much needed social interaction of the evening. This particular cyber café is the only one on the north coast. One might say it’s a luxury. I’m surprised it’s still around considering our cultural stance on superfluous things. Going inside the café, it’s best to wear sunglasses as not to hurt your eyes from all the glowing lights. Flashy gizmos and screens fill the place for your pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a ride on the yellow line to Arborway. No one else got off at the stop, so I expected the place wouldn’t be crowded. This was good, as I hoped to avoid running into friends. I don’t go to the cyber cafe to socialize. In fact, I go to do quite the opposite. This was a time for solitude and individual mediation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opening the door to the café was like opening a magic box. The bells strapped to the top of the door frame jingled as I swung it open. The place was burning blue with light. Soft cushioned seats lay scattered across the lounge area. Each individual one was an odd geometric shape. Dodecahedrons, cylinders, rectangular prisms, et cetera. High tables had built-in touch screens emanating a digital world. People could sit on stools, and poke around on little arcade games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The walls were brick painted black and married to avant-garde art. The smell of coffee assaulted my nostrils. Ambient music seeped through the speakers hanging in the corners of the walls. Layers of winding chords streaked under sparse keyboard notes.
My prediction was correct. The place was quiet at this hour. I timed my visit perfectly, because most people use their Friday evenings for more social based activities. Social interaction. There were a couple of girls sitting on pentagonal prism seats in the back staring at the wall of screens. Each screen showed a different channel. One had a motion picture. Another showed a live concert. And another had a cartoon. With a pair of headphones, one can choose which audio from which screen he or she wants to hear with a click of a button. One screen’s audio can play in one ear while another plays in the opposite ear, allowing for dual absorption. A person could listen to one show while glancing at another, accumulating a collage of sensory experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the far right was a bar. Behind the counter in cabinets were portable headsets and handheld devices to be rented out to customers. There was a row of plastic seats against one wall, each in companion with a footrest. For $300 at the counter, you can get a pair of goggles to strap to your head that fits a small chip the size of a quarter. The small chip contains a mind-numbing, alternate world of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I walked up to the guy at the counter. He was cleaning a mug once filled with a beverage.
“Can I get the one with the restaurant? La Loma?” I asked.
He reached into the cabinet, snatched the chip, and slapped it down on the counter. He then grabbed a pair of goggles from a shelf and handed them to me. The guy must get dozens of people like me every day.
“Enjoy,” he said and I handed him a $300 bill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get thirty minutes. Just thirty minutes to travel to a place you’ve never experienced or touched before. It’s all in your head but it feels completely real. The sights are clear, the scents are potent, and the textures are palpable.
Sometimes, people want a refill. They just pay the $300 again and again and again so they can stay in their nirvana. All so they can disappear to their fantasy world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sat down in the leather seat against the wall and strapped on the goggles. It was a full head apparatus. It covered the ears, the eyes and the nose like a mask. I strapped down my waist to the chair. I clicked the button connected to the goggles and was taken to my place of choice: a deck facing the sea in a restaurant called La Loma. It was the only chip I ever bought. Every time I come to the cafe, I get this exact one, because it’s my favorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chip was designed well. This entire experience, in my opinion, is the pinnacle of art. First, we were given literature and music and paintings. Then we were given photographs and motion pictures. After that we played video games. But now, we have synthetic worlds designed by even brighter men and women.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each setting is a masterpiece in its own right. We can see what they want us to see, feel what they want us to feel, hear, touch, and smell. It’s like reality, but not, at the same time. It can be if we choose. We can ignore the real world and indulge in our fantasies for periods of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;La Loma was my guilty pleasure. It’s set looking out at a sea dubbed “the Mediterranean,” an exotic name I would have never conjured up myself. And perhaps that’s why it’s so captivating. Someone invented that word. Someone had the imagination to put a restaurant against this backdrop. People fill the seats at the tables and talk through their programmed conversations. They sound the same every time. I know because I eavesdrop on them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seagulls cried like sirens in the distance. A thin cloud of fog hovered over the rocks near the water. I could barely hear the music playing nearby because of the constant conversations around me. Platinum utensils clanged against porcelain plates and the smell of food invaded my nose. But my favorite part was not the luxury. It wasn’t that feeling of being high class and attractive. My favorite part was not the gorgeous outlook. It wasn’t even the breathtaking architecture. My favorite part was the people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Would you like anything to drink?” a waitress interrupted my daydream.
She was wearing a fancy black dress. Truthfully, everyone in La Loma was wearing high class attire. It was different from life in the north coast. However, I didn’t care for any of it. Clothes don’t interest me. And why should they? They serve a utilitarian purpose. Why waste time deciding what dress you’re going to wear when you don’t have to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Can, can I have a glass of, wine?” I stuttered and she nodded.
I felt it was an appropriate thing to have in this occasion. In the real world, I prefer not to drink. The waitress brought me my glass of wine and I stared out at the so-called “Mediterranean” while I drank. I felt the maroon colored liquid enter my lips and splash upon my tongue. It’s dark rich flavor invoked images of a thousand fruits gushing across my taste buds.
Behind me were tables seating guests amidst conversations. I turned and looked at them. These half-human constituents of the scene were not programmed to react exactly as a real person would. They don’t mind when I stare at them or when I listen intently to what they say without any contribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard, “Se casó con esa dama. Ya tú sabe”.
“¿Cuánto tiempo se conocen?” said another.
“Seis meses”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were speaking some made up language that I didn’t understand. And perhaps that’s the point. They weren’t saying anything at all. Plain gibberish. It leads me to wonder about the motives of the artist behind this place. Whoever was the genius who did the design, left it all open ended. I can interpret their nonsensical language to be whatever I want it to be.
When my thirty minutes were over, I felt fulfilled. I eavesdropped on conversations. I stared directly into faces. I couldn’t do these things in the real world. But all of these things I could do without consequence while eating dinner at La Loma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sometimes</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 21:28:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/sometimes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A life is a gust of wind.
It will pass by and rattle the leaves of trees firmly planted in the ground.
It will make its presence known and then fade away.
It will pass so quickly that the forest will label it merely a tourist.
Only the leaf can measure the strength of the wind.
The leaf is driven to move and provoked to hiss, but even a leaf’s tantrum can’t attract enough attention.
It takes a storm for the forest to notice – a big storm.
And even storms are common.
Perhaps a tornado or a hurricane instead. A gust is worthless and meaningless.
Sometimes you forget your own existence.
You look around at this foreign place called Earth.
You see people, and you see their habits, emotions, and behaviors. And then you try to put the pieces together and gather a grasping of why.
Place yourself in a any large gathering, in a random town, looking at a sea of unknown but familiar faces.
You’ve never met any of these people, yet you can observe them, and you can acknowledge for a few moments that you aren’t the main protagonist in this literary epic called “mankind”.
These people have lives.
In this small room, you see a mountain in each person.
They were weathered and molded by the people who surround them and what they believe in.
It was only for a moment, but you left yourself.
Now, you’re back inside.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>