<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>motorcyle on andrew colabella</title>
    <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/motorcyle/</link>
    <description>Recent content in motorcyle on andrew colabella</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:30:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://andrewcolabella.com/tags/motorcyle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>edge of the world</title>
      <link>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/edgeoftheworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Apr 2018 21:30:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://andrewcolabella.com/stories/edgeoftheworld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It started with how she would keep her towel wrapped around her after she came out of the shower. We were married for three years and suddenly she was ashamed to walk around the bedroom naked. Then came an abundance of silence at the dinner table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“So how was your day?” “Good”. Then came the nights when she would come home late without any explanation. And then came the divorce papers. It felt like I was falling face first into the pavement in slow motion. I saw the impending crash, but it couldn’t happen fast enough. Three years gone. My nice apartment gone. Most of my furniture and appliances gone too. Three years of just a foggy dream and now I was awake and raw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was heavily involved in the Silicon Valley tech scene. But the gig was turning sour. After the divorce, I started to slouch. I was showing up later and later. My work was getting sloppier. And this all came to a head when I showed up one Monday hungover and disheveled. Shirt stained and unbuttoned. Hair uncombed. And then, BANG. Just like that. Fired.
The stinging pain started to settle in. I thought about what to do. My life was reset, not by choice, but by force. It only took a small accident and a little nudge to get me moving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One morning I woke up to find a magazine in my mailbox. It was addressed to the wrong person. The magazine said, “A Traveler’s Guide to Alaska”. And all these thoughts infected me. I called J. He was my best friend in the whole wide world, and it felt like he was all I had left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said, “yes,” almost immediately. In fact, I was hesitant and he had to convince me.
“This can be an important moment for us,” he said. And then I thought about my life and how I wasn’t even thirty yet. I was still young despite feeling like I lived a million years devoid of any meaningful accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The plan was to ride north on our motorcycles until the road ran out. Two gentlemen- two compatriots riding ten-thousand miles until the ground turns lifeless on the cusp of the Arctic Sea. No turning back until we reach the edge of the world.
I expected things to go wrong and for there to be challenges. But that only excited me more. I needed something to push back against. I needed the forces of nature to try and bludgeon me down into the ground so I could muscle myself back up with all my strength. I fight harder on the comeback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I geared up my Harley and J geared up his Ducati. And boy, are they beautiful bikes in looks and in sound. But to take on the Great Frontier we had to make some modifications: better tires, rugged panniers, protective covering, et cetera.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A week later, on a typical morning in San Francisco, we began our journey. Breakfast at the diner was fast and filling. We said goodbye to friends from town. After some morning caffeine, we cruised across the Golden Gate Bridge and made our way onto the windy Route 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coastal cliffs were jagged. Currents of wind flowed through me. The fields danced between bone-dry yellow and lush green. As we raced through Northern California, the terrain grew larger and the greens grew darker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>